

Summary

I joined the Air Force after high school and spent four years doing analysis and maintenance work. After my enlistment was completed I went to school and completed a BS and MS in Mechanical Engineering. I then went to work in an Aerospace/Electrical/Mechanical engineering cross-discipline area of Defense for 8 years. More recently, I've been attending a coding boot camp (Code Platoon) to become a Full Stack engineer.

Employment

Northrop Grumman

Melbourne, Florida June 2013 to Apr. 2020

**descriptions purposefully kept vague, more details upon requests

- Designed and Optimized Air Vehicle Components
- Designed Test Articles Developed Test Requirements and Supervised Test Article Builds
- Executed Tests, Post-processed Test Results, Produced Test Data Packages, and Presented Test Results to Internal and
- Lofted Computational ElectroMagnetic (CEM) Models, Meshed CEM Models, and Ran Model Predictions Utilizing High Performance Computers (HPCs)
- Developed Software Tools that Automated Tasks (model creation, data processing, etc) and Reduced Design and Analysis
- Lead a Team of 7 Engineers as a Component Lead
- Trained Jr Engineers in Both Theory and Tools Used in Survivability

Sandia National Laboratories

Member of Technical Staff - Structural Dynamics Analvst

Albuquerque. New Mexico Aug. 2011 to June 2013

- Produced Finite Element Models of Various Systems and Components
- Developed MATLAB Software that Ran LS-Dyna to Fit Simulations to Experimental Results
- Wrote MATLAB Scripts to Allow Production of Hundreds of LS-Dyna Analysis Decks Covering Desired Problem Space for Uncertainty Quantification
- Performed Implicit and Explicit Finite Element Simulations Utilizing High Performance Computers (HPCs)

Northrop Grumman

El Segundo, California

- Performed Aerodynamic and Thermal Elastic Stress Analysis using Nastran
- Collaborated in Designing an Aero-Gel Thermal Conductivity Measurement Device
- Mechanical Lead in Design of Automated Web-Handling Material Qualification and Validation Apparatus
- Produced Vehicle Mesh Models Using CATIA & Patran
- Developed MATLAB Program Enabling Faster Post-Processing of Test Data

United States Air Force

Senior Airman, Enlisted

Wonju, Gangwon, South Korea Dec. 2003 to Nov. 2007

- Performed Spectral Analysis of Particulate Air Samples
- Deployed Worldwide to Set Up Portable Clean Rooms and Perform Anlaysis
- Maintained Seismic Array and Ensured Data Collections

Projects

The Jiu Jitsu Guide

Jan. 2020 to Current

TV Guide for streaming Brazilian Jiu Jitsu events

Scavenging Heroes

Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020

YouTube based game show

Brazilian Jiu Jitsu

Fall 2008 to Current

Activities

learning and practicing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu

Contact

jasonpul.github.io/

5624405680

♀ Austin. Texas

in jason-pul/

(C) iasonpul

Education

Mt. San Antonio College

Fall 2007 to Spring 2008

University of Southern California

Fall 2008 to Spring 2010

BS Mechanical Engineering 2010

University of Southern California

Spring 2010 to Fall

MS Mechanical Engineering 2011

Skills

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

CATIA

Solidworks

Patran

Nastran

LS-Dyna LS-PrePost

Cubit

Hypermesh

SURVIVABILITY ENGINEER

SWITCH

GEMS

Ram2d

SFNTRi Saher

RamCat

RamCad

Pioneer

PRODUCTIVITY/MISCELLANEOUS

Microsoft Office Suite

TORQUE

LSF

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Python

NumPy

SciPy

Django

JavaScript

Pandas

React.js

PostgreSQL

IN2

Matlab

Linux Command Line

Object Oriented Programming